Catalog of the Walt Whitman Literary Manuscripts in The Charles E. Feinberg Collection of the Papers of Walt Whitman, 1839-1919, Library of Congress, Washington, DC.
Published by The Walt Whitman Archive in collaboration with the University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries.
- Literary File, 1841-1919, undated (Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37)
  - The Sobbing of the Bells, 1881; loc.00020; xxx.00302; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder The Sobbing of the Bells (1881). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of The Sobbing of the Bells, first published in the Boston Daily Globe on September 27, 1881. On the verso is a letter from John Boyle O'Reilly to Whitman that has been cut up and pasted together.
  - The Sobbing of the Bells, 1881; loc.00022; xxx.00302; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder The Sobbing of the Bells (1881). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of The Sobbing of the Bells, first published in 1881. This clean draft is encased in mylar and housed with five clippings and descriptive cards.
  - The Sobbing of the Bells, 1881; loc.00021; xxx.00302; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder The Sobbing of the Bells (1881). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of The Sobbing of the Bells, first published in 1881. On the verso is prose in Whitman's hand.
  - [I say the stars are not echoes], undated; loc.00042; xxx.00048; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Song of Myself (1855). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of a poem that resembles section 23 of the final version of Song of Myself but whose specific relationship to Whitman's published work is unknown. The draft, though not identical, has many lines similar to the posthumously published manuscript titled [I Am the Poet]. On the verso is a draft of an unidentified prose work.
  - Song of the Open Road, about 1881; loc.00847; xxx.00111; poetry handwritten 12 leaves (Box 29, Folder Song of the Open Road (1856). A.MS. corrected pages.)
    These corrected pages of Song of the Open Road contributed to the 1881 edition of Leaves of Grass.
  - Song of the Redwood-Tree, about 1874; loc.00297; xxx.00118; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 40.5 x 25.5 cm (Box 29, Folder Song of the Redwood-Tree (1874). Proof Sheet.)
    A proof sheet of Song of the Redwood-Tree, first published in 1874, with minor corrections and a note on the verso in Whitman's hand.
  - Songs of Parting, about 1881; loc.00298; xxx.00292; xxx.00294; xxx.00293; xxx.00295; xxx.00413; xxx.00297; xxx.00299; xxx.00300; xxx.00301; xxx.00424; xxx.00308; xxx.00303; xxx.00305; xxx.00306; xxx.00307; xxx.00427; xxx.00304; xxx.00309; poetry handwritten 18 leaves (Box 29, Folder Songs of Parting. A.MS. corrected pages.)
    Corrected pages, many originally appearing in the 1876 Leaves of Grass, of cluster Songs of Parting, containing 17 poems. Opposite a portrait of Whitman, the title page reads, "Songs of Parting, by Walt Whitman, The Poet's Corrected Proof." These corrections were probably intended for the 1881–82 edition of Leaves of Grass. The 17 poems included are: As the Time Draws Nigh, Ashes of Soldiers, Years of the Modern, Thoughts, Song at Sunset, My Legacy, Pensive on Her Dead Gazing, I Heard the Mother of All, Camps of Green, Bathed in War's Perfume, Now Finalé to the Shore, As they Draw to a Close, The Untold Want, Portals, These Carols, To the Reader at Parting, Joy, Shipmate, Joy!, and So Long.
  - [see the profuse sparks like gold], about 1871; loc.00299; xxx.00244; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 4 x 17 cm (Box 29, Folder Sparkles From the Wheel (1871). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of lines that would be revised and published as Sparkles From the Wheel in 1871.
  - Spirit that form'd this scene, about 1881; loc.00300; xxx.00289; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20 x 12 cm (Box 29, Folder Spirit That Form'd This Scene (1881). A.MS. drafts.)
    A late draft of Spirit That Form'd this Scene, which was first published in 1881, written in ink on one side of a sheet and signed in full.
  - Spirit That Form'd This Scene, between 1879-1881; loc.00131; xxx.00289; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Spirit That Form'd This Scene (1881). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of Spirit That Form'd This Scene written in ink, with a few changes, on a writing surface made by pasting together various strips cut from larger sheets. The poem was published in 1881.
  - Spirit that form'd this scene, about 1881; loc.00615; xxx.00289; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20 x 12 cm (Box 29, Folder Spirit That Form'd This Scene (1881). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of Spirit That Form'd this Scene, which was first published in 1881, written in ink on sheets made from pasting together five strips pasted onto another sheet of paper. The date 1881 appears at the top of the sheet.
  - [the arch, the column], about 1881; loc.00616; xxx.00289; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20 x 12 cm (Box 29, Folder Spirit That Form'd This Scene (1881). A.MS. drafts.)
    An early draft of lines related to Spirit That Form'd this Scene, which was first published in 1881, written in ink and pencil.
  - Starting from Paumanok, about 1881; loc.00301; xxx.00047; poetry handwritten 15 leaves (Box 29, Folder Starting from Paumanok (1880). A.MS. corrected pages.)
    Bound proof corrected extensively in Whitman's hand. This correction was probably for the 1881 edition of Leaves of Grass. Opposite a portrait of Whitman, the title page reads, "Starting From Paumanok, by Walt Whitman, The Poet's Corrected Proof—." Starting From Paumanok was first published as Proto-Leaf in 1860.
  - Supplement Hours, about 1881; loc.00302; xxx.00762; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Supplement Hours. A.MS. drafts.)
    Drafts and trial lines for the poem published posthumously as Supplement Hours in 1897. The first line begins "Sane, easy, homely."
  - Supplement Hours, about 1881; loc.00303; xxx.00762; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Supplement Hours. A.MS. drafts.)
    Drafts and trial lines for the poem published posthumously as Supplement Hours in 1897. The first line begins "The lesson done."
  - Supplement Hours Notes, about 1881; loc.00304; xxx.00762; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Supplement Hours. A.MS. drafts.)
    Drafts and trial lines for the poem published posthumously as Supplement Hours in 1897. The subtitle reads "Notes by a half-paralytic."
  - Latter-Time Hours of a half-Paralytic, about 1881; loc.00305; xxx.00762; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Supplement Hours. A.MS. drafts.)
    Drafts and trial lines for the poem published posthumously as Supplement Hours in 1897.
  - [The lesson], about 1881; loc.00306; xxx.00762; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Supplement Hours. A.MS. drafts.)
  - [Notes where wild bees flitting hum], about 1881; loc.00111; xxx.00762; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Supplement Hours. A.MS. drafts.)
  - ?Some Hours of a half Paralytic, about 1881; loc.03275; xxx.00762; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Supplement Hours. A.MS. drafts.)
  - Sword Calls, between 1863-1864; loc.00308; xxx.00742; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 29, Folder Sword Calls (1863-64). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    Draft and notes for an unpublished poem titled Sword Calls written in ink on a large sheet from a notebook (second sheet blank), and in pencil (with "Sword Calls" in red ink) on another smaller leaf.
  - Thanks in Old Age, November 24, 1887; loc.01116; xxx.00357; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Thanks in Old Age (1887). Printed Copy.)
    A clipping from the November 24, 1887 issue of The Republican with Whitman's poem Thanks in Old Age. The date of the issue is noted in Whitman's hand in the margin.
  - Thanks in Old Age, about 1887; loc.01081; xxx.00357; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 29, Folder Thanks in Old Age (1888). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof sheet of Thanks in Old Age that features a single correction—a comma added after the word "retrospective." The poem was published first in 1887.
  - [Thee, in thy orbic singers], about 1872; loc.00310; xxx.00267; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder Thou Mother With thy Equal Brood (1872). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of lines that would appear, in a revised form, first in As A Strong Bird on Pinions Free in 1872, and later under the title Thou Mother With Thy Equal Brood. The leaf consists of two clipped scraps pasted together, and the upper part of the leaf is pasted to a yellow backing sheet that bears writing and sketches in the hand of Horace Traubel. Our images show the front of the leaf, that part of the back visible by lifting the lower part of the leaf, and the reverse side of the backing sheet.
  - Thou Vast Rondure, Swimming in Space, between 1868-1869; loc.00309; xxx.00496; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 32 x 13.5 cm (Box 29, Folder Thou Vast Rondure, Swimming in Space (1868?). Offprint.)
    An offprint of Thou Vast Rondure, Swimming in Space, with note at the top reading "J. T. Trowbridge, from W. W." and a note on the verso reading "is to app. in London Fortnightly for April." Though the poem was submitted in either 1868 or 1869, it was never published in the Fortnightly. It was later incorporated in the poem Passage to India, which was first published in 1871. Thou Vast Rondure, Swimming in Space was not published as a separate poem.
  - A Thought of Columbus, 1892; loc.00328; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
    A complete draft of A Thought of Columbus written on two long strips of various fragments pasted together and three smaller pieces. According to Horace Traubel, this was the last poem Whitman wrote. It was published first in 1892.
  - [The tangled long], about 1892; loc.00329; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft line for A Thought of Columbus. According to Horace Traubel, this was the last poem Whitman wrote. It was published first in 1892. On the verso is a letter from Henry Hopkins dated November 2, 1891.
  - [Deep mystery of mysteries!], about 1892; loc.00330; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of lines for A Thought of Columbus. According to Horace Traubel, this was the last poem Whitman wrote. It was published first in 1892. On the verso is the end of an undated letter from Mrs. John M. Gardner.
  - [Reck'd], about 1892; loc.00331; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of lines for A Thought of Columbus. According to Horace Traubel, this was the last poem Whitman wrote. It was published first in 1892. On the verso is a cut away, undated letter.
  - [An impulse thrilling], about 1892; loc.00332; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
  - A Thought of Columbus, about 1892; loc.00333; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of lines for A Thought of Columbus. According to Horace Traubel, this was the last poem Whitman wrote. It was published first in 1892.
  - [The mystery of mysteries!], about 1892; loc.00334; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
    A draft of lines for A Thought of Columbus. According to Horace Traubel, this was the last poem Whitman wrote. It was published first in 1892. The draft is written on an opened-up envelope from J. H. Johnston postmarked October 30, 1891.
  - Columbus, 1892; loc.00335; xxx.00600; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 29, Folder A Thought of Columbus (1892). A.MS. drafts.)
    A brown envelope that Horace Traubel said contained the manuscript of A Thought of Columbus that Whitman gave him shortly before he died in 1892.
  - To a Locomotive in Winter, 1876; loc.04614; xxx.00273; poetry handwritten 7 leaves (Box 30, Folder To a Locomotive in Winter (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft lines and notes for the poem, To a Locomotive in Winter, first published in the 19 February 1876 issue of the New York Daily Tribune, under the heading Extracts from Two Rivulets. To a Locomotive in Winter was reprinted in the Two Rivulets section of Two Rivulets ( 1876 before being included in Leaves of Grass in 1881.
  - To Get the Final Lilt of Songs, about 1888; loc.00311; xxx.00346; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To Get the Final Lilt of Songs (1888). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof sheet of To Get the Final Lilt of Songs, which was first published in 1888. A note in Whitman's hand, "publ'd in Herald April 16 '88 ," is at the bottom of the page. On the verso is Whitman's prose note serving to coordinate the sharing of proof slips and correspondence within his circle of acquaintance.
  - Veil with their lids thine eyes, O Soul, between 1867-1876; loc.00312; xxx.00791; poetry prose handwritten 3 leaves (Box 30, Folder To the Man-of-War-Bird (1876). A.MS. drafts.)
    One of the notebooks commonly known as the Penitenzia notebooks because that word is written in red ink on the cover, and it includes drafts and trial lines of the poems [Mask with Their Lids] (published posthumously) and beauty (published posthumously).
  - for part in L of G, between 1867-1876; loc.02901; xxx.00791; poetry prose 9 leaves handwritten (Box 30, Folder To the Man-of-War-Bird (1876). A.MS. drafts.)
    One of the notebooks commonly known as the Penitenzia notebooks because that word is written in red ink on the cover, and it includes drafts and trial lines of the poems [Mask with Their Lids] (published posthumously) and beauty (published posthumously). There are also notes about other poems and the arrangement of Leaves of Grass.
  - [Wild, wild the storm and the], May 1880; loc.00257; xxx.00140; poetry handwritten 2 leaves (Box 28, Folder Patroling Barnegat (1880))
    A heavily revised draft of Patroling Barnegat, first published in the April 1881 issue of Harper's Monthly Magazine as Patrolling Barnegat.
  - Thou Who Hast Slept All Night Upon the Storm, between 1876-1878; loc.00314; xxx.00134; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Man-of-War-Bird (1876). Printed Copies.)
    Printed copy of Thou Who Hast Slept All Night Upon the Storm with bibliographic notations and corrections in Whitman's hand. This clipping is from the Philadelphia Progress ( November 16, 1878 ). The poem had been published earlier as The Man-of-War Bird in the 1 April 18 issue of The Athenæum. It was eventually titled To the Man-of-War-Bird.
  - [Bursts the wild storm], about 1876; loc.00313; xxx.00134; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Man-of-War-Bird (1876). Printed Copies.)
    A heavily edited draft of the poem initially published as The Man-of-War Bird and eventually titled To the Man-of-War-Bird. The draft is accompanied by Whitman's note about the poem's first publication in the April 1876 issue of The Athenæum. The note itself is dated March 1876.
  - Thou Who Hast Slept All Night Upon the Storm, between 1876 and 1878; loc.02938; xxx.00134; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Man-of-War-Bird (1876). Printed Copies.)
    Proof of Thou Who Hast Slept All Night Upon the Storm, with corrections in Whitman's hand. The poem was first published as The Man-of-War Bird in the 1 April 18 issue of The Athenæum and finally titled To the Man-of-War-Bird.
  - Thou Who Hast Slept All Night Upon the Storm, between 1876 and 1878; loc.02939; xxx.00134; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Man-of-War-Bird (1876). Printed Copies.)
    Proof of Thou Who Hast Slept All Night Upon the Storm, with bibliographic notations and corrections in Whitman's hand. The poem was first published as The Man-of-War Bird in the 1 April 18 issue of The Athenæum and finally titled To the Man-of-War-Bird.
  - Thou Who Hast Slept All Night Upon the Storm, between 1876-1878; loc.02940; xxx.00134; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Man-of-War-Bird (1876). Printed Copies.)
    Printed copy of The Man-of-War Bird (later published as To the To the Man-of-War-Bird) with a bibliographic notation in Whitman's hand. This page is from the London Athenæum ( April 1, 1876 ).
  - To the Sunset Breeze, about 1890; loc.00315; xxx.00394; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Sunset Breeze (1890). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of To a Sunset Breeze with notations in Whitman's hand. The poem was first published in 1890.
  - To the Sunset Breeze, about 1890; loc.02444; xxx.00394; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Sunset Breeze (1890). Proof Sheets.)
  - To the Sunset Breeze, about 1890; loc.02445; xxx.00394; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Sunset Breeze (1890). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of To a Sunset Breeze with notations and corrections in Whitman's hand. The poem was first published in 1890.
  - To the Sunset Breeze, about 1890; loc.02446; xxx.00394; poetry prose printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Sunset Breeze (1890). Proof Sheets.)
    Proofs of To a Sunset Breeze with notations in Whitman's hand. The poem was first published in 1890.
  - To the Year 1889, about 1888; loc.00077; xxx.00389; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 19 x 21.25 cm (Box 30, Folder To the Year 1889 (1889). A.MS. draft.)
    An early draft of To the Year 1889, first published in January 5, 1889. The poem was later published under the title To the Pending Year.
  - To the Year 1889, about 1889; loc.00316; xxx.00389; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder To the Year 1889 (1889). Proof Sheet)
    Proof sheet of To the Year 1889 (first published in 1889 and later under the title To the Pending Year) with a bibliographic notation in Whitman's hand.
  - The Trail, about 1872; loc.00617; xxx.00743; poetry handwritten 3 leaves 25 x 20 cm (Box 30, Folder The Trail (1872). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    Notes and drafted lines of an unpublished poem, which Whitman had tentatively titled The Trail. The lines were written while Whitman was reading The Oregon Trail by Francis Parkman, for he has noted it at the top of the first page. The title, written near the bottom of the first page, and "The Emigration to California 1846 '7 ," on the third page, are written in red ink. The relationship of this draft to Whitman's published work is unknown. All versos are blank.
  - Twilight, June, 1889; loc.00317; xxx.00367; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 17 cm (Box 30, Folder Twilight (1889). Proof on birch bark.)
    Written in ink, with one line in pencil, are notes on a proof of Twilight, which is printed on a piece of tan birch bark. The notes, in Whitman's hand, read: "Walt Whitman, June 1889 " "on birch bark," and "a curio, on birch bark, Walt Whitman." Twilight was first published in 1887.
  - A Twilight Song, about 1890; loc.00318; xxx.00398; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20.25 x 18.5 cm (Box 30, Folder A Twilight Song (1890). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of A Twilight Song, which was first published in 1890, with corrections in Whitman's hand and with notes from both Whitman and the printer.
  - A Twilight Song, about 1890; loc.00351; xxx.00398; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20.25 x 18.5 cm (Box 30, Folder A Twilight Song (1890). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of A Twilight Song, which was first published in 1890, with notes in Whitman's hand.
  - A Twilight Song, about 1890; loc.00352; xxx.00398; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20.25 x 18.5 cm (Box 30, Folder A Twilight Song (1890). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of A Twilight Song, which was first published in 1890, with a note in Whitman's hand.
  - The Unexpress'd, about 1889; loc.00319; xxx.00407; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 22 x 17 cm (Box 30, Folder The Unexpress'd (1890). A.MS. draft.)
    A heavily corrected draft of the poem The Unexpress'd, which was published first in 1891, written on the verso of a cancelled letter from Marjorie Cook, dated September 25, 1889.
  - Unveil Thy Bosom, Faithful Tomb, April, 1865; loc.00320; xxx.00744; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 7.5 x 17 cm (Box 30, Folder Unveil Thy Bosom, Faithful Tomb (1865). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of an unpublished burial lyric for the death of Lincoln entitled Unveil thy bosom, faithful tomb and dated April, 1865, written in pencil on a scrap of paper torn from a larger sheet.
  - Up, Lurid Stars!, about 1865; loc.00321; xxx.00593; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 16 x 20 cm (Box 30, Folder Up, Lurid Stars! (1865). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft of a poem entitled Up, Lurid Stars! which was never published in Whitman's lifetime. It is related to the poem World Take Good Notice, which was first published in 1865.
  - The Voice of the Rain, about 1885; loc.00322; xxx.00359; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder The Voice of the Rain (1885). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof sheet of the poem The Voice of the Rain, which was published first in 1885, with notations in Whitman's hand.
  - The Voice of the Rain, about 1885; loc.02466; xxx.00359; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder The Voice of the Rain (1885). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof sheet of the poem The Voice of the Rain, which was published first in 1885, with notations and corrections in Whitman's hand (including a rejected title and a notation on the verso).
  - [Hermit Thrush], about 1865; loc.00110; xxx.00217; poetry prose handwritten 4 leaves 10.5 x 6.5 cm (Box 30, Folder When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd (1865-66). A.MS. notes.)
    Notes about the hermit thrush in a small homemade notebook, which are related to lines in the poem When Lilacs Last in the Dooryard Bloom'd, first published in 1865.
  - Whispers of Heavenly Death, about 1870; loc.00323; xxx.00003; xxx.00007; xxx.00294; xxx.00004; xxx.00006; xxx.00010; xxx.00011; xxx.00008; xxx.00014; xxx.00012; xxx.00013; xxx.00015; xxx.00304; xxx.00428; xxx.00042; xxx.00018; xxx.00020; poetry handwritten 15 leaves 20 x 13 cm (Box 30, Folder Whispers of Heavenly Death (1870). A.MS. and printed copy.)
    Mostly mounted clippings of poems taken from Leaves of Grass, stitched and tied with ribbon by Walt Whitman. An autograph title page is followed by pages numbered in red pencil 469-484. One poem, Joy, Shipmate, Joy!, on p. 481 is written entirely in Walt Whitman's hand (see image 23), and other corrections and additions are in Whitman's hand throughout. The poems included are: Whispers of Heavenly Death, Yet, Yet Ye Downcast Hours, As Nearing Departure (later published, in a different form, as As the Time Draws Nigh), Darest Thou Now O Soul, Of Him I Love Day and Night, Quicksand Years That Whirl Me I Know Not Whither (later published as Quicksand Years), That Music Always Round Me, As If a Phantom Caress'd Me, O Living Always, Always Dying, Here, Sailor! (later published as What Ship Puzzled at Sea), A Noiseless Patient Spider, To One Shortly to Die, Joy, Shipmate, Joy!, This Day, O Soul, What Place is Besieged?, The Last Invocation, and Pensive and Faltering.
  - With all the gifts America, about 1873; loc.00324; xxx.00258; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder With All Thy Gifts (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft entitled With all the gifts America, published in 1873 under the title With All Thy Gifts.
  - With Husky-Haughty Lips, O Sea!, 1884; loc.04202; xxx.00340; poetry 2 leaves printed handwritten (Box 30, Folder With Husky-Haughty Lips, O Sea! (1883). Printed Copies)
    Page from the March, 1884 issue of Harper's New Monthly Magazine containing Whitman's poem With Husky-Haughty Lips, O Sea! Also included is a clipping from an unknown newspaper (" '84 " written in Whitman's hand at the bottom) of the same poem.
  - Yonnondio, about 1887; loc.00325; xxx.00350; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 30, Folder Yonnondio (1887). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof of Yonnondio, which was published first in 1887, with notes and corrections in Whitman's hand.